亨利  冷静下来
Henry, I need you to calm down.
我们在帮你
We're trying to help.
不
No--!
你俩都喝点
Drink some of that. Both of you.
这场委员会会议真不赖
Some council meeting, huh?
少了两个人
We're two members short.
我们应该在他们归来之前制定新规矩
I think we should make some new rules before they get back.
我特此宣布  每周三的周二
I hereby declare we have spaghetti Tuesdays
我们都吃意式细面
every Wednesday.
首先我们得找到意式细面
First we have to find some spaghetti.
交给你没问题吗
You okay to take over?
每五到六秒挤一次
Every five to six seconds, squeeze.
当你觉得头晕时
You start feeling lightheaded,
就叫别人来接替你
grab somebody else to take over.
我们轮流来做
We'll take it in shifts.
你想帮我去巡查吗
You want to help me go on my rounds?
好
Yeah.
没问题
Sure.
那样能保住他多久的命
How long will that keep him alive?
只要我们愿意坚持  他就能活下去
Just as long as we're willing to do it.
不管需要多久
As long as it takes.
不  在这不行
No. Not here.
帮我把他抬上来
Help me get him on this.
好吧  但几小时后  亨利死了时...
Okay, but in a couple of hours when Henry's dead--
-格伦  -我们怎么能把他的尸体
- Glenn. - How are we gonna get his body
抬下楼  经过牢房区
down the stairs, across the cell block
经过一扇扇门  同时不让别人发现呢
and through those doors without anyone noticing?
如果发生了那种情况  你得帮我
If that happens-- if-- you're gonna help me.
如果我不在了呢
And what if I'm gone?
闭嘴  帮我把他抬上来
Shut up and help me get him on this.
你们在干什么
What are you doing?
我们把雅各布森先生送去更安静的地方
We're taking Mr. Jacobson to a quieter place.
去我的房里拿那本《汤姆・索耶历险记》吧
Go get my copy of "Tom Sawyer" from my room.
我想让你今晚看完
I want you to read it by tonight.
我们要各司其职
We all got jobs to do.
-那是你的任务  -我看不完的
- That one's yours. - I won't finish it.
为什么
Why?
会太黑的  看不见
It's gonna get too dark.
好吧
Well,
尽量试试
give it your best try.
再喝点茶
And drink some tea.
你以前还没这样做过吧
You haven't had to do this yet, have you?
昨晚深夜时有一个人去世了
There was one late last night.
是萨沙动手的
Sasha did it.
人们没必要看见
People don't need to see it.
我不想让他们看见
I don't want them to.
m 20 0 l 209 0 b 218 0 229 11 229 20 l 229 209 b 229 218 218 228 209 228 l 20 228 b 11 228 0 218 0 209 l 0 20 b 0 11 11 0 20 0
m 115 64 l 115 35 l 171 0 l 177 0 l 133 46 l 143 52 l 179 0 l 184 0 l 159 63 l 229 107 l 229 182 l 145 96 l 135 122 l 207 227 l 137 227 l 115 172 l 115 93 l 126 76 l 115 64 l 104 76 l 115 93 l 115 172 l 93 227 l 23 227 l 95 122 l 84 96 l 0 182 l 0 107 l 70 63 l 45 0 l 50 0 l 87 52 l 97 46 l 52 0 l 59 0 l 115 35
m 325 0 l 355 0 l 332 47 l 354 47 l 399 136 l 369 136 l 328 53 l 288 136 l 257 136 l 325 0 m 467 0 l 497 0 l 474 47 l 496 47 l 541 136 l 511 136 l 470 53 l 430 136 l 399 136 l 467 0 m 545 1 l 583 1 l 583 14 l 568 14 l 568 19 l 583 19 l 583 30 l 568 30 l 568 34 l 599 34 l 599 30 l 583 30 l 583 19 l 599 19 l 599 14 l 583 14 l 583 1 l 611 1 b 616 1 622 6 622 10 l 622 36 l 652 0 l 678 0 l 644 41 l 622 41 l 622 47 l 596 47 l 597 54 l 625 54 l 625 68 l 541 68 l 541 54 l 572 54 l 571 47 l 545 47 l 545 1 m 583 72 l 583 85 l 569 85 l 569 90 l 598 90 l 598 85 l 583 85 l 583 72 l 611 72 b 615 72 621 78 621 82 l 653 44 l 678 44 l 644 86 l 621 86 l 621 103 l 597 103 l 597 136 l 570 136 l 564 126 l 562 136 l 542 136 l 548 107 l 568 107 l 565 121 l 571 121 l 571 103 l 547 103 l 547 72 l 583 72 m 600 107 l 620 107 l 624 124 l 653 89 l 679 89 l 642 136 l 615 136 l 618 132 l 606 132 l 600 107 m 689 0 l 716 0 l 721 15 l 732 15 l 732 30 l 718 56 l 731 56 l 735 100 l 721 100 l 717 59 l 714 64 l 714 136 l 693 136 l 693 79 l 676 79 l 707 30 l 679 30 l 679 15 l 694 15 l 689 0 m 738 0 l 804 0 b 807 0 813 6 813 9 l 813 87 l 794 87 l 794 14 l 756 14 l 756 87 l 763 77 l 763 21 l 787 21 l 787 91 l 798 91 l 798 120 l 820 120 l 812 136 l 778 136 l 778 90 l 748 136 l 723 136 l 756 87 l 738 87 l 738 0 m 257 151 l 275 151 l 297 182 l 319 151 l 337 151 l 304 197 l 304 227 l 290 227 l 290 197 l 257 151 m 337 151 l 355 151 l 377 182 l 399 151 l 417 151 l 384 197 l 384 227 l 370 227 l 370 197 l 337 151 m 425 192 l 447 192 b 445 181 427 181 425 192 l 410 192 b 414 162 458 162 462 192 l 462 206 l 425 206 b 425 210 429 212 433 213 l 462 213 l 462 227 l 433 227 b 412 227 408 203 410 192 m 462 151 l 532 151 l 532 165 l 504 165 l 504 227 l 489 227 l 489 165 l 462 165 l 462 151 m 580 172 l 580 186 l 549 186 b 543 186 543 192 549 192 l 565 192 b 589 192 589 227 565 227 l 532 227 l 532 213 l 565 213 b 570 213 570 206 565 206 l 549 206 b 524 206 524 172 549 172 l 580 172 m 592 213 l 606 213 l 606 227 l 592 227 l 592 213 m 639 172 l 665 172 l 665 186 l 639 186 b 623 186 623 213 639 213 l 665 213 l 665 227 l 639 227 b 603 227 603 172 639 172 m 700 184 b 722 184 722 215 700 215 l 700 229 b 740 229 740 170 700 170 b 660 170 660 229 700 229 l 700 215 b 680 215 680 184 700 184 m 737 172 l 782 172 b 803 172 813 177 813 198 l 813 228 l 799 228 l 799 198 b 799 186 793 187 782 187 l 782 228 l 768 228 l 768 187 l 752 187 l 752 228 l 737 228 l 737 172
仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
更多影视更新请登陆www.YYeTs.com
翻译  冰蓝
翻译  33来了
翻译  Reginamoon
翻译  重案组李Sir
翻译  卫老哥
翻译  爱卿遛小鸟
翻译  送小饭
翻译  送小孩
校对  Lemony  爱卿遛小鸟
校对  米小勒  冰蓝
时间轴  加森  雪贵人
时间轴  marktaotao
特效/后期  、青衣
特效/后期  吉吉
精校/总监  送小孩
行尸走肉
第四季  第五集
格伦呢  他说会来见我
Where's Glenn? He said he would meet me.
他在休息
He's resting.
他没事吧
Is he okay?
他一直在帮我忙  很累了  就这样
He was helping me and he got tired, that's all.
-如果你需要帮忙  我可以来  -我不需要
- If you need help, I can help you. - I don't.
我只是让他有事情做
I was just keeping him occupied.
让他只想着帮助别人
Keeping his mind on helping people.
我可以进去帮你
I can come in there and help you.
不  你不用进来
No, you don't need to.
-这样你可以休息  -不
- You can rest-- - No!
贝丝怎么样
How's Bethy?
她很好
She's okay.
老爸  感觉你要累垮了
Daddy, you look so tired.
的确
I am.
但我扛得住
But I'm fine.
他们很快就会回来了
They could return any minute now.
里面情况很糟
It's hard in here.
但我们能坚持住
But we're holding it together.
能挺过去的
We're gonna make it.
你相信的对吧
Don't you believe that?
当然
Of course.
只要再多坚持一下
Just hold it together a little longer.
拜托了
Please?
宝贝  我爱你
I love you, honey.
我也爱你
I love you, too.
多谢你拦住了她
Thank you for stopping her.
外面总得有人照料
We need someone out there taking care of things.
如果她看见我
If she saw me,
肯定会进来陪我
couldn't keep her out.
我知道你不想骗她
I know you didn't want to lie to her.
我没有骗啊
I wasn't lying.
你看你  这不是在休息吗
Look at you. You're resting.
事情差不多做完了
I'm almost done down here.
要不你去躺着休息吧
Why don't you go lie down?
卡尔  朱迪思  他们还好吧
Carl, Judith, are they okay?
还好  卡萝尔人呢
Yeah. Where's Carol?
格伦  赫谢尔  萨沙呢
Glenn, Hershel, Sasha?
情况很糟  但还撑着  达里尔还没回来
Yeah, it's bad, but they're fighting it. Daryl's not back yet.
瑞克  卡萝尔呢
Rick. Rick, where's Carol?
是她
It was her.
杀了凯伦和大卫
She killed Karen and David.
她是为了防止病毒扩散
She was trying to stop it from spreading.
泰尔西很快就回来了
Tyreese is gonna be back here soon,
所以她还是离开比较好
so I didn't think she should be here.
而且我也不能留她
And I couldn't have her here.
她有车有供给
She has a car, supplies,
应该没问题
she'll figure it out.
我等下告诉你父亲  先别告诉其他人
I'll tell your dad. Don't tell anyone else yet.
好
Okay.
换做是你  你会带她回来吗
Would you have brought her back?
-她承认是她干的吗  -是的
- She said she did it? - Yeah.
那你让她走就是对的
Then you were right to send her away.
不知道我能不能做到
I don't know if I could have.
你可以做到  玛姬
You could have, Maggie.
更难的事你都做了
You've done harder things.
别怀疑自己  我们没这特权了
Don't doubt yourself. We don't get to anymore.
瑞克  行尸越来越多了  比推倒栅栏的那群还多
Rick, the cluster's getting bigger than the one that took the fence down.
-我们得做点什么了  -我们会的
- We need to do something. - We will.
卡尔
Carl?
Carl.
卡尔
Carl?
你还好吗
You okay?
我正想问你呢
I was gonna ask you that.
-我们很好  -没人生病吗
- We're fine. - No one's sick?
没有需要采取措施吧
You didn't have to do anything?
没遇到需要开枪的状况  爸
Haven't had to use my gun, Dad.
朱迪思呢
And Judith?
她跟贝丝在一起
She's with Beth.
很好
Good.
在外面找到了点食物
Found some food on the run.
这里有些水果干
There's a bunch of fruit leather in there.
吃完之后让大家把牙刷了
Have everybody brush their teeth after.
-我们能早点出去吗  -还不行
- Can we come out soon? - Not just yet.
爸  你暴露在病毒下的时候我在你身边
Dad, I was around you when you were in the middle of it.
我也在帕特里克的身边
And I was around Patrick.
我没被传染  我能帮你
I didn't get it. I can help you.
谢了  但是我需要你待在这里
Thanks, but I need you to stay here.
我会的  但是
I will. But,
爸  你不能让我避开
Dad, you can't keep me from it.
避开什么
From what?
避开总要发生的事
From what always happens.
是啊
Yeah.
也许吧
Maybe.
但我觉得我有责任试试
But I think it's my job to try.
谢谢你
Thank you.
不客气
No problem.
让我看看你
Let's have a look at you.
医生是最差的病人
Doctors make the worst patients.
不是所有人都能活下去
Not everyone gets to live.
晚期就意味着病入膏肓
End stage is a point that no one comes back from
无法好转
or they-- or they can't.
我现在就是晚期
That's where I am.
不  你得把精力放到能活下去的人的身上
No, you need to focus on the ones that can make it.
我又做了一些点滴
I made some more IVs.
如果你不准备好失去一个人
If you're not ready to lose one,
你就会失去他们所有人
you're gonna lose them all.
这就像是关灯一样
It's like turning off a light--
一盏一盏地灭掉
it'll happen one after the other.
而且他们还不止是死了这么简单
And they don't just die.
我们能挺过去的
We can hold on.
迦勒
Caleb.
那个牢房区出事后
After what happened in the other cell block,
当我来这里时  带来了这些
when I came in here, I brought these.
躺回床上去  我们的情况还没那么糟
Get back in bed now. We're not that bad off.
等真那么糟时
When we are,
就迟了
it'll be too late.
你不明白
You don't understand.
你还有生存机会
You have a chance.
但得了这病  我们已经死定了
This is it after this.
我不会放弃任何一个人
I'm not giving up on anyone.
至少目前不会
Not yet.
一定保证每个人的门都关好了
Just make sure everyone's doors are shut.
迦勒
Caleb...
一定要保证
Just make sure!
迦勒  你得让我看看
Caleb, you've got to let me look at you.
好吧  赫谢尔
Okay, Hershel.
尽管看吧
Have a look.
喝了我给你的茶
Drink the tea I left you.
我一小时之后回来看你
Gonna be back to check on you in an hour.
大家
Everyone,
回到你们的牢房里
get back in your cells.
快点  回你们的牢房里去
Go on, get back in your cells.
我们把他搬上来吧
Let's get him on this.
去休息吧
Go rest.
你能自己走回你的牢房吗
Can you make it to your cell?
? Go your way ?
? I'll take the long way around ?
? I'll find my own way down ?
? As I should ?
? And hold your gates ?
? There's coke in the Midas touch ?
? A joke in the way that we rust ?
? And breathe again... ?
赫谢尔
Hershel.
这是我们失去的第三个人了
Third one we've lost.
我们在牢区后面火化了他们
We're burning them behind the blocks.
火化了他们
Burning them.
只能这样了
That's what it's come to.
你还好吧
Are you okay?
我昨天还和他聊了斯坦贝克[小说家]
I talked to him yesterday about Steinbeck.
他给我引用了一句话
He told me a quote.
"一个悲伤的灵魂
"A sad soul
比细菌让你死的更快"
can kill quicker than a germ."
所以我不想让他们看见发生了什么
That's exactly why I didn't want them all to see what happens.
我知道他们知道
I know they know,
但我不想让他们看见这一幕
but I didn't want them to see it right now.
他们是在看着你呢  赫谢尔
They're seeing you, Hershel.
他们看到你
They see you
坚持不渝
keep going.
即使选择越来越少
Even after all the choices keep getting taken away.
等我们挺过去
When we get past this thing...
事情不会再像之前那样  对吗
it's not gonna be like how it was, is it?
不会
No.
那算是逃避吗
Was that denial?
对事实视而不见
Not seeing things for how they were?
不
No.
你只是需要缓缓
You just caught a break.
你需要点时间  休息了一下
You needed some time. You got some.
你运气好
You got lucky.
我们都是
We all did.
我还是认为这是上天的安排
I still think there's a plan.
我还是相信这一切事出有因
I still believe there's a reason.
你认为这都是考验吗
You think it's all a test?
生活永远都是考验  瑞克
Life was always a test, Rick.
我得跟你说说卡萝尔的事
I need to talk to you about Carol.
挺住
Come on.
挺住  萨沙
Come on, Sasha.
你知道怎么战斗
You know how to fight.
坚持住
Just hold on.
坚持住  别放弃
Just hold on. Don't give up on me, now.
我刚跟你爸谈过了
I just talked to your dad.
总体来说  他看着还行
He looks good, all things considered.
如果卡尔病了  你会在那儿陪着他吗
If Carl were sick, would you be up there with him?
如果我觉得自己能帮上忙的话
If I thought I could help.
你觉得我帮不上忙吗
You don't think I can help?
该死
Damn.
我很庆幸你和我一起在外面
I'm just glad you're out here with me.
欢迎回来
Welcome back.
我昏过去了吗
I passed out?
你脱水了
You were dehydrated.
逞英雄消耗太大了吧
Being a hero takes a lot out of you.
你明白的
You should know.
我觉得你进这里太蠢了
I thought you were an idiot to come in here.
我以为你必死无疑
I mean, I was sure you were just gonna be a dead foolish man.
我不知道这算不算恭维
I can't tell if that's a compliment.
我不知道我在说什么
I don't know what I'm saying.
我一定是撞到头了
I must have hit my head.
我不相信魔法
I don't believe in magic
或是运气
or luck.
我精心计算
I do the math
从不赌运气
and I don't gamble.
但如果不是你那么蠢
But I don't know if I'd be here right now
我恐怕也活不下来
if you weren't so damn stupid.
你知道吗
You know what?
我就当你是在恭维了
I'm gonna take that as a compliment.
赫谢...
Hersh--
赫谢尔
Hershel--
我过一会儿再来看你
I'll check on you in a little while.
他怎么样
How is he?
在睡觉
He's sleeping.
你自己也该休息会儿
You should get some rest yourself.
我不想离开他  说不定他会醒过来
I don't want to leave him in case he wakes up.
-要我看看他吗  -不用了
- Want me to take a look at him? - No.
让他睡觉就好
Just let him sleep.
赫谢尔
Hershel!
大家都待在房间里
Everyone stay in your cells.
不
No.
去吧
Go.
围栏更重要  我们得加固
The fence is more important. We need to keep it standing.
我来就行
I got this.
-你一个人做不来  -我知道  快去
- You can't do this alone. - I know. Go.
跟我来  亨利
Just follow me, Henry.
来这儿  离开格伦  来吧
Down here, away from Glenn. Come on.
来吧  亨利  快走  走这边
Come on, Henry. Here we go. This way.
快来  乖孩子  来吧  亨利
Come on, boy. Come on, Henry.
再过来一点儿
Just a little more.
继续走
Keep coming.
快来  好孩子  快点儿啊  来吧
Come on, boy. Let's go. Come on.
卡尔
Carl?
Carl...?
卡尔
Carl.
我听到了枪声
I heard gunshots.
我需要你的帮助
I need your help.
过来  下来这儿  亨利
Come on. Down here, Henry.
跟着我来  来这儿
Keep following me. Come here.
再走一点
A little further.
亨利  来吧
Henry, come on--
-你还好吗  -我友好地叫他
- You okay? - I called him nice.
他没有抓伤格伦  我以为说不定他会听我的
He didn't scratch Glenn. I thought maybe he listens.
-丽兹  格伦在哪儿  -他的牢房里
- Lizzy, where is Glenn? - His cell.
爸爸
Dad!
爸爸  把门打开
Dad! Open the door!
回去
Get back in there.
你们俩待在这里
You two stay put in here.
坚持住  格伦  坚持住
Hold on, Glenn. Hold on.
赫谢尔
Hershel!
迦勒  迦勒  我们需要枪
Caleb. Caleb, we need the gun.
你觉得他们还好吗
Think they're okay?
如果情况不妙  我们会听到更多枪响
If things were going bad, we would have heard more shots.
玛姬会来找我们
Maggie would have gotten us.
我们得完成这个
We have to do this.
来吧
Let's do it.
-我自己来就行  -我来帮你
- I got it. - Let me help.
好了  放下来  没错
All right, set it down. All right.
快跑
Run!
爸爸  快来  快点
Dad, come on! Come on!
爸爸  我们怎么办
Dad, what do we do?
也许我能把车开来挡住围栏
Maybe I could back the bus up against the fence.
挡得住吗
Will it hold?
快走
Come on.
装口袋里
Pockets.
给你
Here.
-装好了吗  -好了
- Got it? - Yep.
-好了  听我说  -好
- All right, listen to me. - All right.
弹匣装在这里  保险扣在这里
Magazine goes in here. Release is here.
一定要锁好
Make sure it latches.
拉回拉杆
Pull back the operating rod
推弹入膛
and rounds feed up.
速射时紧压扳机  知道吗
Keep squeezing the trigger for rapid fire, okay?
知道
Okay.
打不过就跑
You shoot or you run.
别让它们近身  明白吗
Don't let 'em get close, okay?
后退
Back off!
撑住  格伦
Hold on, Glenn.
我们有医疗用品
We have something.
应该还在
We still have it.
狗娘养的
Son of a bitch.
爸爸
Daddy!
别  你会打到气囊的  格伦需要它
No! You could hit the bag. We need it for Glenn.
-他在哪  -在上面  100号牢房
- Where is he? - He's up here. Cell 100.
他快窒息了
He's turning blue!
清空他的气道  我马上就来
Clear his airway. I'm on the way.
-爸  -让他仰卧
- Dad. - Roll him on his back.
爸爸
Dad.
压住他的手臂
Hold his arms down.
来吧  孩子
Come on, son.
来吧  你知道流程的
Come on. You know how this works.
放松
Just relax.
撑着点
Stay with us.
Stay with us...
撑着点
stay with us.
你会没事的
You're gonna be okay.
我们都会没事的
We're gonna be okay.
让你别进来的
I didn't want you in here.
我知道
I know.
我必须进来
I had to.
正如你一样
Just like you.
爸爸
Daddy.
让你待在原地的
I told you to stay put.
结束了吗
Is it over?
但愿如此  亲爱的
I hope so, honey.
爸
Dad...
一切都会没事的
everything's gonna be okay.
-萨沙  萨沙还好吗  -我不知道  抱歉
- Sasha? How's Sasha? - I don't know. I'm sorry.
进去吧  外面交给我们
Get in there. We got this.
爸
Dad...?
他们回来了  去休息吧
They're back now. Go rest.
? Go your way ?
? I'll take the long way around ?
? I'll find my own way down ?
? As I should ?
? And hold your gates ?
? There's coke in the Midas touch ?
? A joke in the way that we rust ?
? And breathe again ?
? And you'll find loss ?
? And you'll fear what you found ?
? When weather comes ?
? Tearing down... ?
要帮忙吗
Need some help with that?
不  你去忙吧
No. Do your thing.
你没叫醒我
You didn't wake me up.
我想让你多睡会儿
I thought I'd let you sleep in.
-我应该帮忙的  -很好
- I should help. - Good.
我得去跟达里尔谈谈
I've got to go talk to Daryl.
现在吗
Right now?
不
No.
很快就去
Soon. Soon.
-格伦怎么样了  -他撑过了晚上
- How's Glenn doing? - He made it through the night.
现在能自己呼吸了
He's breathing on his own now.
玛姬和鲍勃跟他在一起
Maggie and Bob are with him.
他情况挺稳定  所以我出来透透气
He seems stable enough for me to get some air.
-他真他妈坚强  -确实
- He's a tough son of a bitch. - He is.
你也真他妈坚强
You're a tough son of a bitch.
-那是  -卡萝尔呢
- I am. - How about Carol?
她在A区陪着丽兹吗
She up in A block with Lizzy?
没有  你去找瑞克吧
No. Talk to Rick about her.
她没事  但你得和他谈谈
She's okay, just talk to him.
你要出去吗
You heading out?
你想来吗
You want to come?
那当然
Hell, yeah.